(
"ai_sub_version": "2.9.1",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 7,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 15,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch"
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 5,
"max": 5,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
WHERE EMOTIONS BLOOM
RAORA PANTHERA BIRTHDAY 2024
TODAY...
5/11 2028 RAORA'S BIRTHDAY
Chattini, let's celebrate together!
BEGINS
Oh my god, that was a good nap!
Wait...
What do you mean? That's not my room?
Huh?
Why... why am I in a white room right now?
How did I end up here?
What?
Uh, white canvas? Huh?
What is this? Why... why is there a white canvas in here?
Eh? What... where is... where is my room? Huh?
Weird.
Huh? Chatino!
Ah! Thank god you're here!
Oh, this place is so scary, Chatino! Where are we?
Chatino? Cha...
Chatino!
Oh... what happened to you?
Come here, don't worry, I got you.
You are kind of heavy, though!
Don't worry Chatino, I got you. We need to find a way out, okay?
We're going to find a way out.
Where... where should we go?
Huh? Why there is a portal now?
Huh? Why is there a portal now?
Should we open it? No?
Fine, I guess we should go in there.
Maybe we're going to wake up. Maybe I'm still dreaming.
Okay...
Issa!
Heave-ho!
Let's go.
You are kind of heavy, though!
Issa!
Heave-ho!
ロンリーガールは いつまでも
Lonely girl is forever dreaming
届かない 夢見て
of an unreachable dream
騒ぐ 頭の中を
Her noisy mind is
掻き回して、掻き回して。
stirred up, stirred up.
「問題ない。」
"No problem,"
と呟いて、
she mutters,
言葉は失われた？
have the words been lost?
もう失敗、もう失敗。
Failed again, failed again.
間違い探しに終われば、
After searching for the odd one out,
また、回るの！
she starts spinning again!
もう一回、もう一回。
One more time, one more time.
「私は今日も転がります。」と、
"I think I will keep rolling on today too,"
少女は言う
the girl says,
言葉に意味を
making sure that
奏でながら！
each of her words is sincere!
「もう良いかい？」
"Are you okay?"
「まだですよ、
"Not yet,
まだまだ先は見えないので。息を止めるの、
I still can't see far ahead. Hold your breath,
今。」
now."
ローリンガールの
A rolling girl feels she has
成れの果て
reached the end
届かない、向こうの色
of an unreachable color on the other side
重なる声と声を
All these overlapping voices
混ぜ合わせて、混ぜ合わせて。
they're all merging into one, merging into one.
「問題ない。」
"No problem,"
と呟いた
she muttered,
言葉は失われた。
but now, those words have no meaning left.
どうなったって良いんだってさ
No matter what happens, it's fine,
間違いだって起こしちゃおうと
even if I make mistakes,
誘う、坂道。
the slope is tempting me.
もう一回、もう一回。
One more time, one more time.
私をどうか転がしてと
"Please make me roll!"
少女は言う
the girl says,
無口に意味を
as her words pile up
重ねながら！
silently with meaning!
「もう良いかい？」
"Are you okay?"
「もう少し、
"Just a little more,
もうすぐ何か見えるだろうと。」
something will be visible soon."
「息を止めるの、今。」
"Hold your breath, now."
もう一回、
One more time,
もう一回。
one more time.
「私は今日も転がります。」と、
"I think I will keep rolling on today too,"
少女は言う
the girl says,
言葉に笑みを
making sure every word
奏でながら！
is said with a smile!
息を止めるの、今。
Hold your breath, now.
Ah! Ah!
Yay!
Ciao, everyone!
Ciao, Chatini!
Hi!
It's me, Raora Panthera from Hololive English...
...Justice-! RAWR!
Big cat means...
...big stage!
Oh my god! Look at this!
Oh!
Huh? What is this place?
Why are we here?
And also, what day is it? What day is it?
Is it... is it... is it my birthday?!
Yay!
Thank you, everyone, for being here on this special day!
I'm so happy to see everyone!
Ciao, ciao, ciao, ciao, ciao!
Hi, everyone!
And talking about my birthday,
I have a special hashtag for today,
which is...
#Raorabday2026!
Woo!
So everyone, make sure, if you want to share some screenshots,
and you want to share some comments on social media,
make sure to use this hashtag! Thank you so much!
Oh, but maybe now we should take a look...
...we should take a look at this stage! Whoa!
It's so... it's so big, isn't it?
It's a little bit like... it looks really dreamy, like...
...it seems like we are in a dream.
Maybe... maybe I'm sleeping? Maybe I'm sleeping?
Whoa, whoa.
It's like... surrealism kind of thing.
What... what is this place? Where am I?
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
Eh? Eh?
Huh? Eh... my... my idol outfit?!
What? Huh?
Why... why my idol outfit now?
Maybe that means... I should sing more?
Well, might as well!
So please,
listen to my songs!
交わした約束忘れないよ
I won't forget the promise we exchanged,
目を閉じ確かめる
I close my eyes to confirm.
押し寄せた闇...
I'll brush away...
...振り払って進むよ
...the gathered darkness and move forward.
いつになったらなくした未来を...
When will I be able to see...
...私ここでまた見ることできるの？
...the lost future here again?
溢れ出した不安の影を
I tear through the shadows of anxiety that have overflowed,
何度でも裂いてこの世界歩んでこう
again and again, I will walk through this world.
とめどなく刻まれた
The time that was carved unceasingly
時は今始まり告げ
now signals the beginning.
変わらない思いをのせ
With these unchanging feelings,
閉ざされた扉開けよう
let's open the closed door.
目覚めた心は走り出した
The awakened heart has started running,
未来を描くため
to draw a future.
難しい道で立ち止まっても
Even if I stop on a difficult path,
空はきれいな青さで...
the sky is a beautiful blue...
...いつも待っててくれるよ
...and will always be waiting for me.
振り返れば仲間がいて
If I look back, I have friends,
気がつけば優しく包まれてた
and realized I was being gently wrapped up.
何もかもが歪んだ世界で
In a world where everything is distorted,
唯一信じれるここが救いだった
this place I can believe in was my only salvation.
喜びも悲しみもわけあえば
If we share both joy and sadness,
強まる想い
these feelings will become stronger.
この声が届くのなら...
If this voice reaches you...
きっと奇跡はおこせるだろう
I'm sure we can make a miracle happen
交わした約束忘れないよ
I won't forget the promise we made
目を閉じ 確かめる
I close my eyes and confirm it
押し寄せた闇 振り払って進むよ
I'll shake off the encroaching darkness and move forward
どんなに 大きな壁があっても
No matter how big the wall is in front of us
越えてみせるから きっと
I'm sure I'll show you I can overcome it
明日 信じて 祈って
Believing in tomorrow, and praying
壊れた世界で 彷徨ってわたしは
Wandering through this broken world, I...
引き寄せられるように 辿り着いた
...finally arrived here, as if drawn to you
目ざめた心は 走り出した未来を描くため
My awakened heart started running to paint the future
難しい道で 立ち止まっても
Even if I halt along this difficult path
空はきれいな青さで いつも待っててくれる
The sky will always wait for me with its beautiful blue
だから怖くない
So I'm not afraid anymore
もう何があっても 挫けない
No matter what happens, I won't lose heart
ずっと明日 待って
And I'll keep waiting for tomorrow
Yay! Woohoo!
Oh! Hug! Hug! Hug!
Happy birthday!
Thank you, Kronii! Thank you!
I'm so excited for you! It's your first 3D birthday live!
It is! And look at us with our idol outfit! Oh, we're so pretty!
We are so gorgeous.
So cool! I'm so cool!
You are.
I am so cool!
And you know, because you're so cool, I want to give you a beautiful color that I think would suit you.
Me?
Yes.
Which color? Pink? Is it going to be pink?
Um, it's...
If you look at your eyes, your beautiful... yellow eyes...
They, they have curiosity and playfulness.
And... I think it suits you.
And so I would like to give this color, this beautiful color around us.
Which color?
Are you color blind?
What?! No!
You don't have to bully me on my birthday! You're supposed to be nice to me!
No, no, I meant your beautiful yellow eyes.
Ah... It's like gold.
Why?! On my birthday, instead of giving me a gift, you come here, you sing and dance with me, and then you just start bullying me! Get out of here!
I complimented you! It's... I complimented your golden... golden eyes! Is that beautiful?
So... so it's kind of like yellow, right?
Ye- yeah, yeah.
So, what does it mean? Why... why did you give this color to me?
I... like...
I just said curiosity and playfulness.
So...
I was listening to you!
You weren't paying attention to me. You don't care about me.
My turn. You talk too much. My turn.
I think you should keep up with your dreams.
I have a question.
Okay! I have an answer.
Like, I was expecting like... blue coming from you.
Why yellow?
Why are you making me laugh?
Is it because of the yellow?
It's...
It's just, this everything is so beautiful.
You're obsessed with my eyes.
Your eyes are so beautiful.
Who was expecting more like a blue? Because I thought you were like... sad...
You don't have a blue color scheme in your...
Oh.
But you... you're blue.
Yeah.
But it's because...
I know! I give you blue!
Oh, thank you!
What's that mean?
Loneliness, sadness, fear, maybe?
Oh. That's... why would you give that to me?
Because...
I thought you liked me.
I like you!
You... you invited me...
...all the way here, I give you this beautiful color...
...and you give me blue?
But I like you! You're so pretty like blue!
I'm so... yeah.
And you're so pretty...
Oh, stop!
Please stop.
Stop! You stop!
You know what? We can maybe blend blue and pink together to get...
Purple.
Yeah. Purple.
Never mind.
What does purple mean?
What does purple mean? I don't know, we'll find out!
Oh wow, purple... You just spoiled it!
We will find out, I guess! I don't know.
There's... to be continued, everyone.
To be continued, everyone!
So keep watching, our...
...my... my... no, our... That's not your birthday, it's my birthday!
It is your birthday!
It is my birthday!
So we're gonna keep watching, everyone! I'm gonna keep singing and dancing for you, okay?
Woo! And be sure to use her hashtag, okay?
Yes!
Hell yeah!
RaoraBDay2026!
Hell yeah! Chao chao!
Chao chao!
Also thank you Kronii for coming.
Oh, yeah, you're welcome.
I forgot to thank you.
Oh yeah, thank you for having me.
Thank you for singing and dancing with me, it was so fun!
Okay, keep up the good work!
Keep... keep the good work!
Yeah, yeah, yeah! Woo!
Let's go! Chao chao!
Chao chao!
Brave Shine / Lyrics: aimerrhythm Music: 小山 寿
[Title Card: Brave Shine / Lyrics: aimerrhythm Music: Hisashi Koyama]
左手に隠した願いは願いのままで
With the wish I’d hidden in my left hand still just that - a wish
覚めない夢見てた
I dreamed of visions I wouldn’t wake from
右手には空の記憶 誰も知らない世界の果て
In my right hand was my empty memory, at the end of a world nobody else knew about
止まない雨に打たれていた
As ceaseless rain pelted me
守りたいものを守れる強さ
The strength to protect the things I’d like to protect
それを信じられなくなる弱さ
The weakness that makes me stop believing in it
全てを受け入れて
Accepting it all for what it is
明日を探す
I go looking for tomorrow
Brave shine 手を伸ばせばまだ
Brave shine, if I hold out my hand, I’ll still find...
Stay the night 傷だらけの夜
Stay the night, a wounded night...
You save my life かざした刃の先に
You save my life, at the tip of the blade I held up
想いを重ねた
My thoughts aligned with it
祈りは時を超えて
Our prayers cross through time
Your brave shine
光ること忘れた青い星が残してく
I watched the lasting shadows left behind
消えない影見てた
By the blue stars that had forgotten how to shine
すれ違う赤の軌道 何も知らない子供のまま
Passing the red tracks like a child who doesn't know a thing
明けない夜を彷徨ってた
I wandered through a never-ending night
失くせないものを失くした弱さ
The weakness that made me lose things I can’t lose
何も信じられなくなる脆さ
The fragility that makes me stop believing in anything
立てなくなっても...
Even when I can no longer stand...
立てなくなっても 運命は進む
Even if I can't stand anymore, destiny proceeds.
Break down
崩れ落ちてゆく 星座が傷つけあう夜
In this night where crumbling constellations hurt each other...
You're breaking dawn
交わした言葉の中に
In the words we exchanged...
独りを支えた
that supported me when I was alone...
確かな夢を 抱えて
I carry a certain dream.
守りたいものを 守れるのなら
If I can protect what I want to protect...
すべてを受け入れて 明日を探す
I accept everything and search for tomorrow.
夜明けを灯す
I'll light the dawn.
Brave shine
手を伸ばせばまだ
If I reach out my hand, it's still there.
Stay the night 傷だらけの夜
Stay the night, in this night covered in scars...
You save my life
重ねた涙の果てに
At the end of the tears I've piled up...
光を見つけた
I found light.
祈りは時を超えて
My prayers transcend time.
Brave shine
Wow! Happy Birthday, Raora!
Happy Birthday! 誕生日おめでとう！
Happy Birthday! Happy Birthday!
Happy Birthday!
Shall we introduce ourselves?
Of course! Please do!
Okay, 自己紹介お願いします、先輩。
Okay, please introduce yourself, Senpai.
Introduction, okay? Yes, please!
こんやっぴー！ホロライブ4期生の、えっと、オールド先輩の...
Kon-yappi! Hololive 4th Gen's, um, old senpai...
常闇トワ様です！イェーイ！
...Tokoyami Towa-sama! Yay!
Old senpai! Yay yay yay!
オールド先輩か...
Old senpai, huh...
Eh? Old senpai? Oh, really?
ちょっと待って... Calliope is only a little bit younger in that case than Towa-sama!
Wait a minute... Calliope is only a little bit younger in that case than Towa-sama!
What? Okay, fine.
Hello, えー、みなさん。Old senpai, Mori Calliope desu. Yay!
Hello, um, everyone. I'm the old senpai, Mori Calliope. Yay!
Hololive English -Myth-. What's up, fellow pink?
Fellow pink! Pink is powerful!
Yay! Pink is powerful!
Towa-sama, you're also pink.
Pink? Me? I'm pink?
Pink, kind of! Of course, different shades of pink, right?
Yeah, the colors are so important in this life, so we must say that this is the pink team, right?
Pink team!
Pink-purple team!
Pink-purple team! よろしくお願いいたします。
Pink-purple team! Please support us!
Yay!
Nice, wonderful! But you know, the lighting actually when we were singing the song that we just sang a moment ago was blue.
Yeah, was blue. So pretty, right? Look at that.
What kind of emotion do you think the blue represents?
どんな感情？Blue?
What kind of emotion? Blue?
Blue?
ブルーは結構寂しいとか...
Blue represents feeling lonely...
ちょっとそういう悲しいみたいなイメージはあるけど、でも、綺麗なイメージもあるよ。
...or having a sad image, but it also has a beautiful image too.
Yeah, also beautiful. Sad, lonely, also beautiful.
For Calliope, I think sometimes maybe there's some fear, right? 怖さ。A little scary, right?
For Calliope, I think sometimes maybe there's some fear, right? Fear. A little scary, right?
But, you know, emotions are beautiful, right? 感情がめっちゃ美しいと思う。Right?
But, you know, emotions are beautiful, right? I think emotions are really beautiful. Right?
So positive, negative, either way, I think colors are really beautiful.
I agree with you! And you know, even if sometimes we have fear and we're scared of doing something, maybe...
maybe we should overcome, we should do our best to, you know...
怖くても、we have to do our best, right? 頑張らないといけないね。
Even if we're scared, we have to do our best, right? We have to keep trying.
Yes!
For example, singing on stage together, speaking Japanese, it's so scary! You just got to try your best...
...throw your fears away. 怖くないよ。
...throw your fears away. It's not scary.
How do you overcome? It's so scary!
We just sang Brave Shine! Brave Shine! We just sang, so...
It's such a good song, it's very fitting.
Right? Yeah, fight your fears! 怖くないね。勇気持って。Courage. And, yeah, challenge your dreams!
Right? Yeah, fight your fears! It's not scary. Have courage. Courage. And, yeah, challenge your dreams!
Yeah, but fears are also part of our lives, right? Like, maybe if we're not... if we don't feel the fear, then...
how can we overcome? Like, how can we do... how to say... how can we do...
I don't know the word... like...
How can we challenge our past selves?
How can we challenge ourselves and do our best every single day, right?
怖くなかったら、well, it's not a challenge, right? チャレンジじゃないよね。
If we weren't scared, well, it's not a challenge, right? It wouldn't be a challenge.
うん、うん、確かにね。
Yeah, yeah, that's true.
怖かったらもっと...
If you're scared, even more...
強くなれると思う
I think you can become stronger.
Yeah!
かっこいいね！ おおー！
That's so cool! Oh wow!
ラオラ意味深い。Deep meaning! That's cool!
Raora, that was so deep! Deep meaning! That's cool!
かっこいい
Cool.
かっこいいね！ Cute and cool, Raora.
So cool! Cute and cool, Raora.
No, no, no!
You are cool!
Everyone here is cool! みんなクール！
Everyone here is cool! Everyone's cool!
Team Pink is very cool. Pink is a cool color, okay?
Well, happy birthday to you.
Thank you so much, Mori-sama.
お誕生日おめでとう！ Happy birthday!
Happy birthday! Happy birthday!
Thank you for singing Brave Shine with me.
It's a very meaningful song and I really appreciate to have my dai-senpais with me. Thank you so much!
It's a very meaningful song and I really appreciate to have my great senpais with me. Thank you so much!
Yeah, of course, old senpais. Old senpais here with you.
Well, myself and Towa gotta get out of here, but Raora, you keep on keeping on, okay?
Okay, I'll do my best!
Yeah, and we'll see you guys later, okay?
See you guys later!
Bye everybody! See ya! Bye-bye!
白い世界の中では
In this white world,
時間が止まってゆくような気がした
it felt like time was stopping.
いつも見せないような表情が
That expression you never seemed to show me...
その距離が 少しだけ愛しかった
I loved that distance, just a little.
巻き戻せないと
"It can't be rewound,"
はしゃいでいるその横顔
you said, looking so cheerful.
抱えていた悩みも ちっぽけだ
Even the troubles I carried felt so small.
君に染まる視界が
This view painted in your colors,
かじかんでく両手が
these hands frozen with cold...
心から願うよ 終わらせたくなどはないんだと
I wish from the bottom of my heart that this will never end.
思い出の中にはいつも君の姿
In my memories, you are always there.
夢のまま 覚めないまま その笑顔が忘れられないや
Remaining in a dream from which I can't wake, I can't forget that smile.
言葉では足りないようだ 大人になんてなれないよ
Words don't seem to be enough, and we can't grow up.
くだらない事ばっか それでも楽しかった
It was full of meaningless things, but it was still so much fun.
ずっと今がこのまま続いたらいいね
"It would be nice if the present could go on forever,"
なんてさ 僕にはにかんでみせるの 泣きそうな声で
you said to me with a bashful smile, in a voice that sounded like crying.
ずっと今がこのまま続いたらいいね
I wish this moment would go on forever like this
今度は僕から会いに行ってみせるの 約束しよう
This time, I will be the one to go see you, let's make a promise
約束をしよう
Let's make a promise
世界は終わりを告げようとしてる
The world is about to signal its end
誰にももう止められはしない
No one can stop it anymore
――始まる
--- It begins
崩壊のシンフォニーが鳴り響いて
The symphony of collapse resonates
降る雨はまるで涙の音色
And the falling rain sounds just like tears
教えて
Tell me
支配し支配され人達は
Will people, who control and are controlled,
いつかその心に憎しみを
ever hold hatred in their hearts...
そして愛することを思い出せず
...and forgetting how to love...
争うの？
...end up fighting?
この歌が聴こえてる
To all those who are hearing my song—
生命ある全ての者よ
all you living souls,
真実はいのちの胸の中にある
the truth lies within your heart.
嵐の海を行く時も
Even when going through stormy seas,
決して臆することのない強さを
it will give you a strength that will never be daunted...
くれるから
...because it's there for you.
けれども進むほど風は強く
But the further you go, the stronger the wind blows,
希望の灯はやがて消えていく
and the light of hope soon fades away.
「明かりをよこせ」と奪い合い
They snatch it away, saying "Give me the light,"
果てに人は殺し合う
and in the end, people kill each other.
涙などとうに枯れて
Their tears have long since dried up.
気付いて
So please realize
その目は互いを認めるため
that your eyes are for recognizing each other,
その声は想いを伝えるため
that your voice is for conveying your feelings,
その手は大事な人と繋ぐために
and that your hands are for joining...
ある
...with those important to you.
この歌が聴こえてる
To all those who have nowhere to turn in this world—
世界中の寄る辺なき者よ
who can hear my song,
希望はあなたの胸の中にある
hope lies within your heart.
燃え盛る焔の中でも
Even amidst burning flames,
決して傷つくことのない強さを
it will give you a strength that will never be damaged...
くれるから
...because it's there for you.
その手で守ろうとしたものは
Was what you tried to protect with those hands
愛する者だったのだろうか
someone you loved, I wonder?
紅く染まったその手を眺めて
Looking at those hands stained red,
やっと自らがしてきた
you finally realize
愚かさを
your own foolishness...
この歌が聴こえてる
This song is being heard
生命ある全ての者よ
To all those who are alive
真実はあなたの胸の中にある
The truth lies within your heart
嵐の海は静まった
The stormy sea has calmed down
失ったものは数えきれなくとも
Even if the things lost are countless
あぁ...
Ah...
この歌が聴こえてる
This song is being heard
世界中の寄る辺なき者よ
To all the helpless people in the world
希望はあなたの胸の中にある
Hope lies within your heart
悲しみの夜を越える時
When you overcome the night of sadness
必ずあなたは生きていく強さを
You will surely have the strength to live on
あぁ...
Ah...
持てるから
Because you will have it
あー！できた！できた！
Ah! We did it! We did it!
できた！イェーイ！
We did it! Yay!
あつい、あつい。
So hot, so hot.
もふもふテール！ あ、しっぽ見せて。
Fluffy tail! Oh, show our tail.
おお、揺れてる。
Whoa, it's swaying.
揺れてる、揺れてる。 1、2、3...
Swaying, swaying. One, two, three...
どっちが大きい？
Which one is bigger?
私の方が長い！ 私のはもふもふ！
Mine is longer! Mine is fluffy!
イェーイ！ここに来てくれてありがとう。
Yeah! Thank you for being here.
彼女を見て！見て！
Look at her! Look at her!
まず自己紹介してね。 あ、はーい！
You should introduce yourself first. Oh, hi!
あなたは誰？この謎の生き物は誰？耳は何個あるの？
Who are you? Who is this mysterious creature? How many ears do you have?
私は謎の生き物。
I'm a mysterious creature.
1、2、3、4...
One, two, three, four...
4つ！4つだよ、4つ！ 5、6、7...
Four! Four of them, it's four! Five, six, seven...
6、7、8個の耳。 もう、やだ。
Six, seven, eight ears. Oh, geez.
あなたは誰？自己紹介して！ストップ！
Who are you? Introduce yourself! Stop!
ハロー！チャッティ！ハイ、デリコです。4つの耳を持つ狐で...
Hello! Hi, Chatty! Hi, I'm Delyko, and I am a, yeah, four-eared fox...
そして、こちらの誕生日ガールの自称親友です！ハハ！
...and self-proclaimed best friend of birthday girl over here! Haha!
私のこと大好きなんだよね？ 大好きだよ。
She loves me very much, doesn't she? I love her very much.
イェーイ！ イェーイ！
Yeah! Yeah!
お祝いに来てくれて本当にありがとう...
Yeah, thank you so much for being here to celebrate...
呼んでくれてありがとう！一緒に踊れて本当に良かった。
Thank you for having me! It was so nice to dance with you.
今日はあなたにたくさんの情熱と決意を届けるために来ました...
I have come here today to bring you a lot of passion and determination...
毎日美しいアートを描く時に解き放つべき情熱をね！
...that you need to unleash when you're doing your beautiful art every single day!
情熱！決意！これからは超情熱的になるよ！
Passion! Determination! I will be very passionate from now on!
今すぐ解き放って。もう待てない。ずっと踊ってたんだから。情熱をちょうだい！私に...
I need you to unleash it now. I can't wait any longer. I've been dancing this whole time. Give me passion! Give me a...
ペンをちょうだい！タブレットを！何でもいいから！
...pen, give me a tablet! Anything!
やるんだ！解き放て！悪魔を解き放て！情熱を見せて！
Just do it! Unleash! Unleash the demon! Show the passion!
解き放つ！ごめんねみんな、もう行かなきゃ。見てくれてありがとう...
Unleash! Sorry, guys, I have to go now. Thank you so much for watching...
違う、それじゃない！その決意じゃない！そうじゃない、それじゃないよ！
No, not that! Not that determination! Not that doing, not that!
あなたが続けて。ライブを引き継いで。みんなありがとう、私は行くね。
You will continue. You continue my live. Thank you so much everyone, I'm gonna leave you.
だめ、行かせない！私を置いていかないで！
No, she won't! Don't leave me!
置いてっちゃうよ。 だめ！
I'm gonna leave you. Don't!
次の曲のダンス知ってる？
Do you know the dance for the next song?
すごく楽しいよ。
It's gonna be very fun.
え、私も参加していいの？
Ay, you want me to join?
そう、そう！ううん、今すぐライブやらなきゃ、見せてあげて。
Yeah, yeah! No, no, you have to do the live now, let's show them.
今すぐライブやるの？もう？よし、準備はいいよ。
I have to do the live now? Already? All right, I'm ready.
見せて、見せて、見せて！
Show me, show me, show me!
うわあああああ！
Uaaaaargh!
よし！決意を解き放て、そうだ、そうだ、そうだ！
Yes! Unleash the determination, yes, yes, yes, yes!
そして次は、誕生日ガールの番！
And now, birthday girl time!
うわ、うわ、うわ、うわ！
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa!
ヘイ、ヘイ、ヘイ。
Hey, hey, hey.
見ちゃった。見ちゃった。
I saw that. I saw that.
見てない、見えてないよ。
You can't, you didn't see that.
みんな見えた？私は見えたよ。
Did you see that? Because I saw it.
あ、見えてないよ。見えてない。ステージから見るべきだよ。
Ah, you didn't see it. You didn't see it. You should see it from the stage.
私たちのピンクと黒の組み合わせって...
Our pink and black together is...
すべて見えたよ、他には何も見えてないよ！
You saw everything! You did not see anything else!
もう、すごく乱暴だね、でもいいよ！素晴らしい、決意がみなぎってきてる！
God, you're so violent, that's good! That's good, the determination is coming out!
情熱が溢れ出してる！情熱を解き放て！ 情熱的になるよ！
The passion is coming out! Unleash the passion! I'll be passionate!
情熱を、お願い。テンション爆上がりだから、お願い、落ち着いて。私には無理。
The passion, please. I'm hypemaxing, please, relax. I can't do that.
ごめん、ごめん。 よし、おいで、おいで、おばあちゃん、おいで。
Sorry, sorry. Okay, come here, come here, grandma, come here.
これで大丈夫。
This is okay.
彼女は話したがってる、絶対に話したがってるよ。
She wanted to talk, she definitely wanted to talk.
話したい！何について話す？
I want to talk! What do you want to talk about?
あなたが話したがってるって言ったの。 話したい。
I said you wanted to talk. I want to talk.
私をおばあちゃん呼ばわりするなんて、よくもそんなことを！よくもそんなことを！
You called me grandma, how freaking dare you! How freaking dare you!
ちょっと、ちょっと！ こっちおいで！こっちおいで！
Hey, hey! Come here! Come here!
自称おばあちゃんは誰？ 私はすごく落ち着いてるよ！
Who is the self-proclaimed grandma? I am very much relaxed!
私が繰り出すこれらすべての動き、ほら、クレイジーなダンスとか。
All these moves I pull out, you know, like all the crazy dance.
本当にタフなダンスだったよね？
Yeah, yeah, yeah. That was such a tough dance, was it?
あぁ、本当に大変だった。 彼女が夕食を奢ってくれるんだ...
Oh, it was so hard. She's gonna treat me for dinner...
...彼女の誕生日のお祝いにね。 そう、私の誕生日！
...to celebrate her birthday. Yeah, it's my birthday!
そう、そう！ あなたが、あなたが私に夕食を奢るべきだよ。
Yes, yes! You should, you should treat me for dinner.
誕生日の主役さん、私に何を買ってくれるの？
What are you gonna get for me, birthday girl?
実は...
Actually...
...make good points here!
No, no, no, no, no...
Oh yeah, because you guys know...
Now, close the camera. No, this is fine.
Why?
I am so... she said, "I am so nice."
Now that I'm done, I'm going to give you...
...$10!
Absolutely not!
Yeah, thank you!
That hasn't happened!
Thank you!
Thank you, thank you!
No!
It's over!
You know my data for the payment, okay?
Hey, hey, come back!
I don't want to send you money anymore!
Oh yeah, you got it.
You owe me £40 already, mate.
You got it, friend taxes, okay?
She's so in debt with me, I swear.
Friend taxes.
This is really bad...
It's my birthday, I decide what I want,
I decide everything!
And, yeah, I want $10, you're going to give me $10.
What should I do?
What should I do? The drama...
Chatty, please tell her!
Chattini, I can't... I can't.
Tell her to give me $10!
You look so determined.
A requirement!
You really want this money.
Fine.
Here it is! Just buy yourself some candy and shit.
Yay! Thank you!
I'm over it. I'm so done.
I live on stream!
Oh my god, it's over.
The mortgage...
Oh, the car...
Oh, the insurance...
It's okay, it's okay!
Oh, it's over.
Ah, it's okay. Don't talk about negative things now, because today is my birthday, we gotta celebrate!
But did you bring cake for us?
Ah... yes.
Where is it?
Actually...
The cake?
Uh...
I'm waiting!
I-I can't talk right now.
Cake, cake, cake, cake, cake...
It's in the other room! It's in the other room!
Cake, cake, cake...
It's in the...
Cake!
No, no, that's my tail!
Hey, hey, I grabbed your tail!
Come here!
No, no, no!
It's kind of easy to get. It's very long.
Listen, listen, listen...
You need to walk... you need to run way faster!
If you want me to... No, no, no, no!
Oh, you know what then? I'll grab yours!
Here it comes!
I got it, I got it!
I'm grabbing it!
I'm going to take a bite!
My tail! Ah!
Oh, manager's done!
My manager! Ah!
Oh, manager's done.
My manager's going to... My manager's not...
And she's not going to be happy with it!
You know what? I'm going to go and talk to your manager by myself!
No, you cannot talk to my manager! I talk to my manager!
I'm so done.
I'm done.
No, you're not. Okay, actually we're done.
That was tough!
That was such a great workout, we really did deserve cake after all.
Ah, we deserve cake after all, isn't it?
What's your favorite flavor?
My favorite flavor is...
Rico tail!
Ah!
Okay, we have to go now. We have to go.
Oh, no! There's more to come! There's so much more! She has so many surprises for you!
You were the surprise.
Am I? No, am I? No, no.
But I have more surprises.
She does, she does, she does.
So, thank you so much...
Happy birthday, Raora!
...Rico!
Yippee!
Rico!
Thank you for having me!
Pink panther! Pink panther!
Great panther!
Oh, yes!
Actually, talking about color, she should put some colors on.
Oh, I bought some new glasses, they are nice and red, you should see them. I'll show you sometime soon.
Ah!
Yippee!
Let's continue!
More songs!
More songs to come!
Happy birthday!
Yeah! Thank you, Rico!
Chattini!
Okay, then, ta-ta!
Bye-bye!
Bye!
We got it, we did it! We ran out of...
言って。
[Song: Say It]
あのね、
Hey,
私実は気付いてるの
I actually realized it
ほら、君が言ったこと
Look, what you said
あまり考えたいと思えなくて
I didn't really want to think about it
忘れてたんだけど
So I'd forgotten about it
盲目的にもう動的にもう想的に生きて...
Living blindly, rashly, delusionally
衝動的な焦燥的な消極的なままじゃ
Impulsively, impatiently, passively—
駄目だったんだ
that wouldn't do.
きっと人生最後の日を前に思うのだろう
Surely, I'll think before the final day of my life
全部全部言い足りなくて惜しいけど
That it's regrettable I didn't get to say everything
あぁ いつか人生最後の日 君がいないこと
Ahh, someday on the last day of my life, you won't be here
もっと
More
ちゃんと
Properly
言って
Say it
あのね
Hey,
空が青いってこと どうやって
how should I convey to you
伝えればいいんだろうね
the blueness of the sky, I wonder?
夜の
And how
雲が高いってこと どうすれば
can I get you to understand
君もわかるんだろう
how high the clouds are at night?
言って
Say it
あのね
Hey,
私実は気付いてるの
I actually already know
もう君が逝ったこと
that you've already passed on.
あのね
Hey,
分からず屋って言うんだろうね
You'd probably call me a stubborn blockhead, right?
忘れたいんだけど
I want to forget, but...
もっとちゃんと言ってよ
More, tell me properly
忘れないようにメモしてよ
Make a memo so I don't forget
明日十時にホームで待ち合わせとかしよう
Let's meet at 10 o'clock tomorrow at the train station platform, or something like that
牡丹は散っても花だ
Even if the peony petals scatter, it's still a flower
夏が去っても追慕は切だ
Even if summer is gone, the longing remains earnest
口に出して
Put it into words,
声に出して
say it out loud,
君が言って
you say it.
そして人生最後の日 君が見えるのなら
And on the last day of my life, if I am able to see you,
きっと人生最後の日も愛を歌うのだろう
surely I'll be singing my love on the last day of my life as well.
全部全部無駄じゃなかったって言うから
I'll say none of it, none of it ended up being for nothing,
あぁ いつか人生最後の日 君がいないことが
Ahh, someday on the last day of my life, you won't be here-
まだ信じられないけど
I still can't believe it, but...
もっと
More
君が
You-
もっと
More
ちゃんと
properly
言って
say it.
Thank you so much for being here, Mio-senpai, Okayu-senpai!
イェーイ！イェーイ！
Yay! Yay!
I can't believe we sang together!
So fun!
Yeah, Mio, thank you!
Thank you! Thank you!
次のゲストはミオ先輩とおかゆ先輩です！
Our next guests are Mio-senpai and Okayu-senpai!
イェーイ！
Yay!
ラオラ、ハッピーバースデー！ハッピーバースデー！
Raora, Happy Birthday! Happy Birthday!
おめでとう！おめでとう！
Happy Birthday! Happy Birthday!
ありがとう！ありがとう！
Thank you! Thank you!
来てくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming!
こちらこそ！
Thank you too!
Mind introducing yourselves one more time?
自己紹介お願いします！
Please introduce yourselves!
オッケー！
Okay!
うち、うちだよ！
It's me, it's me!
狼ミオだよ！
I'm Ookami Mio!
ホロライブゲーマーズの狼ミオです！
I'm Ookami Mio from Hololive Gamers!
可愛い！
So cute!
そして、
And next...
はーい！
Yes!
もぐもぐ、おかゆ！
Mogu mogu, Okayu!
ホロライブゲーマーズの猫又おかゆです！
I'm Nekomata Okayu from Hololive Gamers!
もぐもぐ、もぐもぐ、もぐもぐ...
Mogu mogu, mogu mogu, mogu mogu...
I'm gonna eat you up!
もぐもぐ...
Mogu mogu...
ヤムヤム！ヤムヤム！
Yum yum! Yum yum!
Thank you so much! ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much! Thank you so much!
よし、いくぞ！
Alright, let's go!
ミオズ・イングリッシュ・チャレンジ！
Mio's English Challenge!
イェーイ！
Yay!
The rules, right?
Singing in the concert was beautiful, wasn't it?
Yeah! It was! It was really beautiful!
Hey, Okayu's English challenge!
Cyan symbolize sincerity and self-acceptance.
Cyan symbolizes sincerity and self-acceptance.
And you don't have to try to be strong or try to be perfect.
That's right!
Just accept yourself as you are, and go with the flow, and you'll be fine.
Oh! Can I be strong?
Strong cat? I wanna be a strong big cat!
Big cat! Yay!
Raora strong cat! Raora strong cat!
Thank you, senpais, for your nice words! Thank you!
Thank you! Thank you! Thank you!
心に響きました。
It really touched my heart.
よかった、よかった。
I'm glad, I'm glad.
And here! From here, I've got some exciting news for you guys!
It's about the Raora Panthera Birthday Celebration 2026!
So, please senpais, help me out, okay?
Okay! Okay!
グッズ紹介、お手伝いします! 任せてー!
We'll help you introduce the merchandise! Leave it to us!
Okay! So, Raora Panthera 誕生日記念 2026...
Okay! So, Raora Panthera Birthday Celebration 2026...
グッズの、ご予約受付...
pre-orders for the merchandise...
...スタート! Let's go! So, take a look here!
...have started! Let's go! So, take a look here!
こちらどうぞ。おおー!
Here you go. Oh!
So good! Look at this illustration! Do you like it?
おお、すごい可愛い! めっちゃ可愛いよ!
Oh, it's so cute! So cute!
The illustration was drawn by Komiya-sensei! Thank you so much for making this beautiful art! I'm so happy!
胡宮先生に描いてもらったみたいです! ライブのラオーラをテーマに描いてもらったみたいですね。
It seems it was drawn by Komiya-sensei! It looks like it was drawn with the theme of Raora's live concert.
Okay! So, let's take a closer look at the details! First up, this one!
Long sleeve t-shirt!
おお、ロンTシャツ! ロンTシャツ!
Oh, a long-sleeve T-shirt! Long-sleeve T-shirt!
It features a motif logo on the back, and there is also design on the sleeve. So it's really, really cool for everyday life! So, please check it out!
It features a motif logo on the back, and there is also a design on the sleeve. So it's really, really cool for everyday life! So, please check it out!
可愛い! 後ろにロゴとかも付いててね、いっぱいデザインが凝ってて可愛いですね。
Cute! With the logo on the back and a very elaborate design, it's really cute.
And next, we have... Ta-da!
Body bag! ボディバッグ!
Crossbody bag! Crossbody bag!
And it's a perfect design for everyday use, that lets you show off your love for...
...me, cat! Big cat! Big cat! Big cat!
...me, the cat! Big cat! Big cat! Big cat!
ラオーラ推しアピールできる、普段使いできるバッグになっております!
It's a bag for everyday use that lets you show off your support for Raora!
Thank you! Next up is... Ta-da!
Crying Chattini plushie!
おお、可愛い! チャッティーニ! チャッティーニ!
Oh, cute! Chattini! Chattini!
Crying Chattini, that's what you deserve! That's what you get!
まあまあまあ...
There, there, there...
The crying Chattini comes with an amazing pouch!
Next, please! Next, please!
Ta-da! おおー!
Ta-da! Oh!
Perfect! You can combine them together!
チャッティーニが洗濯機の中に閉じ込められちゃったみたいです! ウォッシュウォッシュ!
It looks like Chattini got locked inside the washing machine! Wash wash!
ぐるぐるぐる... ぐるぐるするの? ぐるぐる...
Spin spin spin... Is it spinning? Spin spin...
はい、こちらね、チャッティーニが閉じ込められているのはぬいぐるみ用のマルチポーチですね。
Yes, this multi-pouch with Chattini trapped inside is for plushies!
And next up is... Ta-da!
Voice pack!
It's going to be fun to listen to it, so please check it out!
はい、ラオーラがね、頑張って収録したボイス、聞いてみてくださいね、皆さんね。お願いします。
Yes, please listen to the voice lines that Raora worked hard to record, everyone! Please do.
And there is also a bonus for purchasing all, the full set! And here it is!
And there is also a bonus for purchasing all of them, the full set! And here it is!
おおー!
Oh!
Cheki-style photo with handwritten message sign.
An instant photo-style card with a handwritten message sign.
サイン、サイン！
Sign, sign!
こちらは直筆サイン入りのチェキ風ブロマイドカードがフルセットに付いてきます！
This comes with an autographed instant photo-style card in the full set!
わぁー！すごい！
Wow! Amazing!
And cheki-style bro- bromide... English 難しい...
And instant photo-style bro- bromide... English is hard...
English 難しかった？ Difficult English!
Was English hard? Difficult English!
With foil-stamped repro-reproduction... I can't... I can't talk anymore! Signature! Woah!
ちなみにサインは数量限定となっております！
By the way, the autographed ones are limited in quantity!
はい！お願いします。 お願いします！
Yes! Please check it out. Please do!
Here's the full set again, so please go check it out, everyone! Thank you, thank you!
And that was the merch line-up for Raora Panthera Birthday Celebration 2026!
Mio-senpai, Okayu-senpai, thank you so much for your support! Thank you so much!
いやいやいや、こちらこそ！上手にフォローできてたかな？できてたかな？
No, no, thank you as well! Were we able to support you well? I wonder if we did.
Thank you! でもすっごく楽しかったです！
Thank you! But it was so much fun!
楽しかった！ So happy! 楽しかった、ありがとう、嬉しい！
It was fun! So happy! It was fun, thank you, I'm so glad!
Alright, now that the merch announcement is done, the next song will be the last one, 最後。
Alright, now that the merch announcement is done, the next song will be the last one.
え？ Last song? Last song! 楽しみ！
Eh? Last song? Last song! Looking forward to it!
Hmm, I'm kind of nervous... Please cheer for me, okay, Senpais?
おーけー、おーけー！ がんばれがんばれ、ラオラ！ファイト、ファイト！ ありがとう！
Okay, okay! Do your best, Raora! Fight, fight! Thank you!
じゃ、bye-bye? Let's say goodbye? おーけー、おーけー！ Bye-bye!
Well then, bye-bye? Let's say goodbye? Okay, okay! Bye-bye!
Bye-bye! Bye-bye!
Draw. / 作詞・編曲：Orcaにゃん
Draw. / Lyrics & Music Arrangement: Orca-nyan
夢のぬくもりと
Warmth of a dream
指先に絵の具の匂い
And the scent of paint on my fingertips
湿ったキャンバスの上には
On the damp canvas
まだ知らない色が息をする
Colors I don't know yet are breathing
All the pieces I picked up
Unravel in my own chest
“It's okay,” I whisper softly
Saying it back to myself
迷いも 震えも
My hesitation or my trembling
隠さなくていいから
I don't need to hide
この線の全部が
All of these lines
私へ続く
Lead to me
I'm drawing out my true colors
滲んだ輪郭も
The blurred outlines too
淡く、脆く、煌めいて
Faintly, fragilely, sparkling
形になってゆくの
They become a form
夜明けの面影に 集めた色を重ね
In the shadow of the dawn, I layer the colors I gathered
Draw it slow, draw it true
夜明けの夢現
Dawn's dream-reality
微睡に余白の答え
An answer in the margins of a doze
白いページに色が咲いていく
Colors bloom on the white page
息づいた景色を描き出す
Drawing out the scenery that has come to life
All the colors I held back
Start to gather in the hush
“It's all right,” the first light tells me
Sending warmth into my heart
願いも希望も 隠さなくていいんだよ
I don't need to hide my wishes or my hopes
ほら、ありのままの 私を描く
Look, I am drawing myself as I am
At last, hold my true colors
ほどけた輪郭も
The unravelled outline too
そっと、ずっと、重なって
Softly, always, layering
私の形になる
Becoming my shape
静かな始まりに
At the quiet beginning
目覚めた色を抱いて
Holding the colors that awakened
I'm drawing out my true colors
滲んだ輪郭も
The blurred outline too
淡く、脆く、煌めいて
Faintly, fragilely, glittering
形になってゆくの
Becoming a shape
夜明けの面影を
The traces of dawn
集めた色で描く
Painting with the colors I gathered
Draw it slow,
draw it true
Ah...
La la la...
Draw it slow,
draw it true
夢のぬくもりと
With the warmth of a dream
指先に絵の具の匂い
The smell of paint on my fingertips
ありふれた朝の先には
Beyond the ordinary morning
まだ知らない色が
Colors I still don't know
溢れてる
Are overflowing
Draw it slow, draw it true
らおー！
Raooo!
Ciao everyone, I'm still here!
I, I just wanted to say thank you...
so, so much for watching my first ever birthday live!
I had so much fun, and I hope you, I hope you had so much fun too!
I worked really, really hard, and I'm so happy right now, so...
thank you Chattini! Thank you everyone for watching!
見てくれてありがとうございました！
Thank you so much for watching!
So, I have to go now!
Bye-bye!
And remember, big cat means... big trouble!
らおー！
Raooo!
Ciao everyone, I have one last message for you all!
Be sure to check out the MV premiere right after this!
And also, my new original song will be released on all streaming platforms on May 11th, midnight, in your local timezone.
So don't miss out, okay?
Also, go check out my merch!
Bye-bye-bye!
らおー！
Raooo!
Bye-bye!
[On-Screen Text]
THANK YOU to all my Chattini!
For all the love and support you have always given me!
[On-Screen Text]
THIS WAS MY VERY FIRST 3D BIRTHDAY LIVE!
And I hope you all had as much fun as I did! RAOOO!